Arshad Nizamdeen

Founder of Flex Technologies



My Contact

Arshadlivephd@gmail.com

+94 77454 1184

No.132/2 Bulugohathenna, AKurana

www.Arshad.flex.lk

Personal information

- Name Arshad
- Age 28 years old
- Gender Male
- Born in 10-05-1995
- Marital status Married

Experienced In

- WordPress Based Projects
- Shopify Projects
- Magento 2
- Mobile Application development (Andromo)
- php Laravel based Projects
- Quick Book Accounting

Skills

- Fast learner and Problem-Solving
- Strong leadership and team management skills
- Thinking Innovative
- Attention to detail
- Project management
- Budgeting and financial management
- Specialized in Advance Excel Reporting.

About Me

I am the founder of flex Technology with a passion for innovation and a drive to create transformative solutions. With over a decade of experience in the industry, I bring a wealth of knowledge and expertise to every project. My focus is on delivering cutting-edge technology that empowers businesses to succeed in today's fast-paced digital landscape.

Professional Experience #1

Flex Technologies | Founder 2019 - 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Creating strategic plans to achieve the company's goals and objectives.
- Developing a clear and compelling vision for the company's direction and growth
- Develop and execute a technology strategy that aligns with the organization's overall business goals.
- Manage the IT department's budget, ensuring that resources are allocated effectively and efficiently.
- Provide leadership and guidance to IT staff, including coaching, mentoring, and training.

Achievements

2019-2021	WordPress projects.
2021- 2023	Become a Shopify partner and sold 300+ Shopify stores.
2022-2023	Have sold Digital applications via Flippa for more than 5000\$ to USA Based Clients
2023	Deployed a Digital Marketplace to Sell Digital products to end users. Readymade application (Dropshipping, Dropservicing, Mobile apps etc) - https://www.noxce.com/

Have completed more than 2001

Professional Experience #2

Saleh Al Hamad Al Mana Co. National Car Rental (QATAR) – | IT Executive 2018 - 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Assisting with IT Manager- Server Configuration, troubleshooting issues & Visiting other branches for Maintenance.
- Identifying Static Solutions for Technical & Recurring problems.
- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.

Professional Experience #3

Golden Bird Farms (Pvt) Ltd – | IT Administrator 2015 - 2017

Key responsibilities:

- Providing recommendations when it comes to improving the organization's IT systems.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems, and networks and making sure that backups of all data are taken and securely stored.
- Maintaining and upgrading operating systems, databases, and software applications, ensuring that they are up-to-date and secure.
- Maintaining and enforcing IT security policies and procedures, including access controls, user authentication, and antivirus and malware protection.
- Managing and maintaining IT inventory, including hardware and software licenses, and ensuring compliance with software licensing agreements.

Professional Experience #4

Wariyapola Groups (Pvt) Ltd – | Assistant System Administrator 2013 - 2014

Key responsibilities:

- Assisting co-workers with everyday IT needs & Providing technical support across the company.
- Provide orientation and guidance to users on how to operate new software and computer equipment

Professional Experience # 5

Nimspring Pvt Ltd – | IT Support Executive 2012 - 2013

- Install and configure appropriate software and functions according to specifications.
- Providing telephone and email support to customers to troubleshoot their problems.
- Diagnose Hardware and software faults and solve technical and application problems.
- Maintain records/logs of repairs and fixes and maintenance schedule.

Education Background

BCS-UK (British Computer Society) Bachelor Degree
 The Chartered Institute For IT

Completed in 2018

- MCSA (Microsoft Certified Solution Associates)
 Become A Windows System Administrator (Server 2012 R2) Completed in 2017
- CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associates)

 E-win Networks

Completed in 2017

DICT and DIE

Diploma In Information Communication Technology (DICT) Completed in 2013 And Diploma In English (DIE)

O/L - Ordinary Level - Successfully Completed
 Azhar College Akurana - Kandy, Sri Lanka

Completed in 2011

Certification

- DICT (Diploma in Information Communication Technology) March 2013
- DIE (Diploma in English) March 2013
- BCS -Certificate level (UK) June 2014
- BCS Diploma level (UK) March 2016
- Cisco CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associates) Switching and routing November 2017
- CCNA Security (210-260) Cert Prep:1 Security Concepts (Lynda) November 2017
- Windows System Administrator 2012 R2-MCSA (10 Certifications, Certified Each Module) (Lynda) -December 2017
- Learning VMware vSphere (Lynda). November 2017
- Create a **Subnet**. (Cybrary). June 2017
- PCI/DSS (Payment Card Industry Data security standard) (Cybrary)- October 2017
- CompTIA Cloud + (Cybrary). September 2017
- Cryptography (Cybrary). December 2017
- Microsoft PowerPoint 2010 (Alison). December 2017
- Microsoft Word 2010 Revised 2017 (Alison). December 2017
- Microsoft Access 2010 Revised 2017 (Alison). December 2017
- Ethical Hacking & Cyber Security Workshop. January 2018

References

M.S.A Shibly (Managing Director) at Golden Bird Farms. Contact No. +94 777656650 Email: Shibly50@yahoo.com

Shamri Ahafurdeen (General Manager) at Esoft Metro Campus (MSc in Strategic Marketing, MSc in IT, PGD IT, MBCS CITP, MCS, AMACS) Contact No. +94 77 3099325. Email: Shamri@esoft.lk